The Legend Begins
Tarzan II is a adventure, animation, family film directed by Brian Smith.
When one of his missteps puts his family in jeopardy, Tarzan
decides they would be better off without him.
Tarzan (voice), played by Harrison Chad.
Zugor (voice), played by George Carlin.
Uto (voice), played by Brad Garrett.
Kago (voice), played by Ron Perlman.
Mama Gunda (voice), played by Estelle Harris.
Kala (voice), played by Glenn Close.
Tarzan II (also known as Tarzan 2 and Tarzan 2: The Legend Begins) is a 2005 American animated direct-to-video adventure comedy film and the third Disney's Tarzan film
after Tarzan and Jane, though it chronologically takes place during the events of the original film set during Tarzan's childhood, years before he met Jane.
It was produced by Walt Disney Pictures and Disneytoon Studios with animation outsourced
to Toon City Animation, and distributed by Buena Vista Home Entertainment.
Taking place during Tarzan's youth and before his adulthood, the film
follows Tarzan's adventure to discover who he really is.
Glenn Close and Lance Henriksen reprise their roles as Kala and Kerchak from the first film while Harrison Chad, Brenda Grate,
and Harrison Fahn are the new voices for the younger versions of Tarzan, Terk, and Tantor, replacing Alex D.
Linz, Rosie O'Donnell, and Taylor Dempsey.
They are joined by new characters voiced by George Carlin,
Estelle Harris, Brad Garrett, and Ron Perlman.
Tarzan II was released on DVD and VHS on June 14, 2005.
The film explores themes of cartoon, feral child, tarzan, prequel, jungle.